

# Marco Richetta

- marcorichetta.vercel.app | in marco-richetta
- marcorichetta

#### **About Me**

I'm a software engineer with +5 years of experience, mostly focused on **backend** and **API development** with **Python**, covering the entire process from system design, data modeling, implementation, testing, documentation, deployment, and observability. I also have experience with **DevOps** tasks and frontend with **React**.

I like to share knowledge by giving <u>talks</u>, being a <u>mentor</u> or simply helping others to solve problems. <u>E.g. the Django forum</u>.

Currently interested in working on **Developer Experience (DX)**, specially through IaC. Also learning about Go, MLOps, <u>Elixir</u>.

## Experience

Fullstack Developer, Freelance - Copenhagen, Denmark

Dec 2024 - present

- Software development of a live/on-demand content streaming platform. My tasks are varied since we work on a product made from scratch.
- Stack NextJS, Express, Typescript, Serverless Framework, AWS (Lambda, Cloud-Formation, RDS)

**Software Engineer**, Mercado Libre - Córdoba, Argentina

Jul 2022 - Jun 2024

- Worked improving Python DX, maintaining tooling used by thousands of developers in the company. (General support, features, bugfixes, version deprecation).
- Building on our Python expertise, we led upgrades for over 1,000 outdated Java applications and libraries using <a href="Large-Scale Code Changes">Large-Scale Code Changes</a>, managing the roadmap and collaborating with responsible teams to implement and monitor each update.

Fullstack Developer, Flux IT – Córdoba, Argentina

Jan 2021 - Jun 2022

- Fullstack development (React/Django) to integrate 3rd party systems with internal company applications.
- Later, in a more **DevOps** role, I helped in the migration of the internal infrastructure to Kubernetes applying **GitOps**. This also led to better DX.

- I helped designing new features and bugfixing for a <u>clinic history management</u> <u>system</u> made with **Django**.
- I worked both in the frontend and the backend, defining and updating Django models, views, forms and templates of the system. Also made **tests** for every functionality added or modified.
- As a necessity, I configured a Django/Postgres development environment with Docker. This greatly improved my familiarity with the technology allowing me, for example, to optimize images build time or to debug inside the container with VSCode.

IT Support, Prodeman S. A. - Córdoba, Argentina

Sep 2017 - Sep 2018

- My general goal was to provide **technical support** to all the employees on the company on everything referred to IT.
- Responsible for managing video surveillance systems, including hardware (analog & IP cameras such as Vivotek and Hikvision) and software (Nuuo Video Management Software).
- Office365 tasks (Users administration, Mailbox backups, Powershell scripting)

### Education

**BS** Computer Systems Analyst, Instituto Superior 25 de Feb 2015 - Dec 2020 Mayo - Córdoba, Argentina

## Volunteering

<u>Hack Your Future</u>: Joined as a Technical mentor to help people kickstart their programming careers

## **Skills**

Programming Languages: Python, JavaScript/Typescript, Go

**Technologies:** Django, Pytest, React, Kubernetes, FluxCD, Docker, OpenTelemetry

Languages: Spanish (native), English (professional proficiency), Italian (A1), Danish (learning)